Alexander Scovell – Curriculum Vitae

Contact No: 07940206352; Email Address: alextscovell@gmail.com;

Contact Address: 28 Edenhall Avenue, Manchester, Greater Manchester, M192BG

Professional Summary

I am a friendly and dedicated individual with a keen interest in data, its uses and its larger implications in business and society. I was educated at the University of Leeds.

My experience working in Data Protection for AQA (a large charity) impressed upon me the importance of data management and analysis within the workplace.

My recent enrolment in the Generation UK Data Engineering course, run in conjunction with Infinity Works, has provided me with the necessary technical skills and experience with key technologies used for manipulating data and databases in a professional setting. I am making sure my skills remain up to date by undertaking the 'Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp' on Udemy and working on my own projects.

Technical Skills

- Python
- SQL
- ETL/Data cleansing
- Data manipulation (NumPy, pandas)
- AWS (S3, Lambda, CodePipeline, Redshift, IAM etc.)
- Web scraping (Selenium, BeautifulSoup)
- Source control using GitHub

Experience

Generation UK & Ireland

Data Engineering Bootcamp, August 2020 - November 2020

- Learned database fundamentals including database/table creation, data insertion and data normalization.
- Got hands on experience with key database technologies such as Snowflake, Google BigQuery, MySQL and AWS RedShift (PostgreSQL).
- Worked in a small group, using agile methodology, to develop an Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) pipeline using several AWS services and infrastructure as code (serverless) written in Python.
- Other topics covered in the course included cloud computing, big data, web scraping and machine learning, as well as other professional soft skills needed for success in the Data/Tech industry.

AQA

Data Protection Administrator, August 2019 - February 2020

- This role incorporated a large amount of customer facing and internal communications, via both email, phone and CRM (MS Dynamics) helping to ensure our organisation remained GDPR compliant.
- Produced monthly reports, utilising my skill in both Excel and Word, showing team performance across a range of metrics.

- Worked as part of a small team to organise the company archives, ensuring all was compliant and ordered appropriately. This required a fair amount of business travel and hence, also required dedication to the role.
- Dealt with customer queries regarding GDPR issues via email or our CRM system.
- Hosted and produced agendas for team meetings, collating the larger teams' points and agendas for presentation.

AQA

Marking Administrator, May 2019 – August 2019.

- Worked through a large volume of exam scripts daily (500+), ensuring they were correctly formatted for examiners. This required both a keen eye for details and the ability to work quickly and to a deadline.
- Trained in safeguarding procedures, ensuring the students whose papers I saw were showing no signs of distress or calls for help. This often required a delicate and discreet approach.

Naas Electrical

Labourer, May 2018 - May 2019.

- My duties while employed with Naas Electrical included a range of first and second-fix rewiring electrical duties (routing cable, installing sockets etc.)
- This job often had a high degree of autonomy, with my employer trusting to leave me at job sites alone with a set of tasks to complete. I enjoyed this sense of responsibility and liked working to complete large scale jobs independently.
- Working with precision was a must as any small mistake could lead to damaging someone's home and my employers' reputation as a 'Which?' trusted trader. This really helped hone my eye for detail.

Education

University of Leeds, 2:1 HNDip in Geological Sciences, September 2014- June 2017.

- Developed both logic and critical thinking skills to aid with problem solving, this was especially useful completing higher level mathematics modules.
- Use of analytical skills to collate and sort data.
- Trained in a suite of analytical and mapping software, highly computer literate.
- Extensive research driven essay experience; a thorough grasp of the English language.
- My team working skills were improved through weekly practical sessions where the aim was to cooperate in small groups to solve a range of problems. These included topics such as engineering, climate management and environmental clean-up.
- Unfortunately, I was unable to complete my degree due to a medical problem I suffered from at the time, I have since recovered to full health.

Aquinas College, September 2011 – July 2013.

A-Levels: Biology, Chemistry, Maths

As-Levels: Biology, Chemistry, Maths, History

Priestnall High School, September 2006 – July 2011.

GCSE's: 10 A*-C including A's in English, Mathematics and Science

Extra-curricular: I was a College Leader from Year 9 onwards, and in Year 11 I was made head boy. This involved public speaking duties, event organisation and liaising with staff members to bring up concerns and ideas as a representative of the student body.